Did you know there's an awesome
treasure hidden at the end of the sea?
And anyone who finds it,
the King of the Pirates!
Is that exciting or what?
There are incredible adventures
out there just waiting for us!
Bon voyage, have the courage
that sail and believe,
and we will see a glimpse of the sunroar.
Back when we first started,
we had separate horizons,
sailed toward different dreams.
Things have changed now,
for together we found, we looked
through the spyglass and see.
And we know that our hearts
have brought us here.
Where the conscious point's our destiny.
There's no looking back,
take the hell with me!
We can't stop all our
troubles, forget the past.
Though the future's
unclear, we still can smile.
We know we'll get the regrets.
Every tear that we pride only helps.
Saw dreams come true.
You and those dreams
are precious in my life.
A glimpse of the sun
rising on our tomorrow?
A snake!
Wait just a minute.
Hey, Kalgara, look at this.
What a shock.
I didn't realize that
snake had a grandchild
that snake
huh would
you look at that it
doesn't make any sense those two were trying
to kill each other not too long ago now
they're laughing together
like good friends
usually Kokoro isn't
very friendly with the
villagers either I've never seen him smile
like that before we climb
down here climb down
that ringing kalgara
where's that beautiful
ringing coming from follow
me and i will show you
Oh, my God.
They're here!
You're speechless.
I'm not surprised.
This is Shandora, and we're the
survivors of this golden city.
A city of gold.
It's like I'm dreaming.
It's a city full of treasure!
There's gold everywhere!
Hey! Wait!
Everyone stop!
It's all right.
Load up your ship with
all the treasure you can.
Just leave the Golden Bell!
All the villagers here
agree that this is right.
It is a gift.
We want to thank you for saving our
tribe from that terrible disease.
This is nothing at all
I don't understand haven't your people
been working hard to protect this city.
That's true.
We have worked hard to protect it
Although, it's not necessarily
the treasure we guard.
Come, let me show you.
The only thing we guard is this stone.
Look at that writing.
What's it mean?
We don't know.
It is a poneglyph, writings
left over from ancient history.
You mean this isn't something that
was written by your ancestors?
There is only one thing we know for sure.
That the city of Shandora fought and
fell trying to protect this stone.
And we will too.
We feel it is our duty to continue
to protect it with the same resolve.
This stone now represents proof that our
ancestors not only fought a vicious fight,
but survived.
And we revere our ancestors as
we would our gods. But still,
when I heard the bell ringing before,
I had no idea it would be this huge.
It's to them. Words?
Yes.
It speaks so that the spirits
of our ancestors who have passed
can still return to this land at
any time without getting lost.
We continue to ring the bell as
if to shout to them, We are here.
Come home.
We are waiting for you.
And the sound?
The sound itself proclaims
the glory of Shandora,
making its existence known
to the ends of the sea.
It shouts, we will never run or hide.
Because of this, we have
given the Grand Bell a name.
We call it the Fire of Shandora.
Makes sense.
That explains the majestic sound.
You think so? Yeah.
It was this fire that reached out
to us and helped us arrive here.
I heard the ringing
during a terrible storm.
I heard it clearly when it
shouldn't have been audible at all.
You like the bells ringing too?
Yeah, I bet you do.
I bet someday you'll grow up
just like that other giant snake.
But probably not for
another hundred years!
Noland, I invite you to stay here.
Please, it's been 400
years since Shandora fell.
And you're the first guest we've
had, so I want to welcome you.
Won't you accept my offer?
Thank you, Kal 'gara.
And with your permission,
I would also love the opportunity
to collect some plants
from the forest and see this
plague all the way through.
Commodore!
Hold on now.
What's with the clothes?
We found an eternal compass.
And look at this map, Commodore!
Just look!
We took these items from
those who intruded upon us.
Yes, that skull shape is
definitely our island.
The name Shandora means
the skull's right eye.
The name refers to the
city's location right here.
Well, take care.
And make sure she gets
plenty of rest, okay?
I will, thanks! Goodbye, Doctor!
Hey look everyone!
Nolan brought us some exotic crops!
I have a greenhouse on our ship
with all kinds of plant samples.
I'll leave some seeds and sprouts
here that are suited for your soil.
Ha!
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
All right, time to begin
another day of hard work.
Hard work doing what?
Having a campfire party?
But why?
Why would the doctor
and the others do this?
Chief, Noland and the others are coming.
You are not to say
anything about last night!
Is that clear?
They said they are going
to set sail in a few days.
So until then.
Don't do anything rash!
Do you hear me? Fine then.
Our people will never
understand each other.
They've only done harm.
I don't care how good his medicine is.
He's still a god killer.
Do these people think they can just show
up here and stomp all over our history?
They'll pay.
We must endure it, and we must
wait quietly for them to leave.
They're here.
Hello, everyone.
I'm looking for Kalgara.
Why is everyone acting
so cold all of a sudden?
And where's Kalgara?
Turn around and leave now.
You're not welcome.
You're outsiders.
Kalgara doesn't want to see you anymore.
Seto, stop!
When are you going to leave anyway?
Answer me!
What's going on it seems like
they suddenly hate us now
hold on you can't just start
acting like this it's not fair
let it go let's continue our
work we still have some forest
to inspect there you are
Kalgara Nolan has been looking
for you.
I know he has.
I have no desire to speak to him.
If I see him right now, I'm afraid I might
kill him.
That's strange.
The bell didn't ring today.
Yeah, it's the first
time that's happened in
the month that we've been here.
Commodore?
I'll be done exploring
the forest in two days.
Uh, right.
Let everyone know we
set sail in three days.
Tell them this is their last chance
to enjoy dry land for a while.
Commodore, to tell you the truth, I
can't wait to get off this insane island.
Only after we finish our duties.
Good night.
You should stay here, Noland.
I have an idea.
Why don't you make Moose your wife?
Don't be silly.
I have a family at home
and kids who are her age.
You're outsiders.
Kalgara doesn't want to see you anymore.
When are you going to leave anyway?
Answer me!
I know you're here, Kalgara!
Come out, now!
I won't understand what's
going on unless you talk to me!
This is ridiculous!
Not to mention unfair! Hey!
Come on, we set sail in a few days.
I don't want us to part like this.
How dare you show your face here?
Do you want your wife to
live her life as a widow?
The Commodore seems sad lately.
Yeah, it's unfortunate.
He thought he made such
a good friend out here.
None of this makes any sense.
It looks like we're going to set
sail first thing tomorrow morning.
The villagers are so upset
that we can't go near them.
Plus, I don't remember ever
hearing the bell ring today.
How dare you show your face here!
Do you want your wife to
live her life as a widow?
I gotta say, this is definitely
a tough way to leave.
Idiot!
Why did I believe he was a botanist?
Damn you, Noland!
If these are the unfortunate
victims of your advancement,
then we never should have accepted
you or trusted you the way we did.
Kindred trees?
Yes.
We've been told that the spirits of
our ancestors who died on this island
are guided back by the sound of a bell
so that they may rest inside them.
Since the age of Shandora,
every one of our ancestors who
lived on the island watches over us.
They watch over us from
those sacred white trees.
Important to us Shandians.
That is why we've protected them
as we've protected our own lives.
It's more than just a forest.
It's our history.
Can you see now why we
hold these trees sacred?
And we just chopped them all down.
The warriors felt so betrayed and angry,
they grabbed their weapons
in search of revenge.
We must drive them off this island!
Alright!
But because you had already saved so many
lives here they couldn't just I understand
They were so grateful
that they couldn't act
on it but doctor even
if it was just for tree
Research even if you
didn't know the villagers
anger won't go away so
before you go I thought
I'd ask. I...
I have to know the reason why.
So their ancestor spirits
are in those trees.
I can't believe I didn't know.
And now we've done something
terrible that we can't reverse.
They have every right to
be as angry as they are.
But, Commodore, we had no choice...
There are no excuses.
I was too wrapped up in my own
interests to even consider theirs.
I was told that besides
proclaiming the city's existence,
the Bell also served as a guide for
their ancestors to return to the island.
And we just cut them down.
We do not deserve their forgiveness.
Commodore, wait.
You want us to leave the treasure behind?
I just found out Nolan and his
men are getting ready to leave.
Moose, where have you been?
What if...
What if you knew a single tree
was tainted by the forest,
spreading from tree to tree, from
tree to people, and killed the island?
What if you knew about it beforehand?
What are you talking about?
Please, tell us what you mean.
If we had a choice,
what would we do with that one tree?
What would we do?
Father, listen.
You have to stop them. You fool.
Don't you understand what they've done?
We can't leave things this way.
We'll regret it forever.
You finally made such a dear friend.
And we owe them so much!
Father, we can't leave
them hurting like this!
What are you talking about?
There is no excuse, but on the
Commodore's behalf, I must say this.
Those woods were already dead
before we arrived on this island.
The worst thing about tree fever
is that it also infects plant life.
Commodore Noland understood this, and
that was his reason for doing what he did.
This is also why he pleaded with
you without regard for his own life.
From people to forest
and forest to people,
several small islands have been
destroyed in exactly the same way.
Killed by fever.
But there's nothing to worry about.
Yesterday, we finished inspecting
the rest of the forest.
I'm sorry we cut down your
forest without knowing,
and I feel worse that we
never explained why we did it.
It's probably unforgivable,
even with an explanation.
But a botanist would never harm
a forest without good reason.
Trust me, the Commodore doesn't have
anything against gods or spirits.
It's just that he always
has to make a choice,
and he always knows
what is most important.
So, that means that they did all
of that to try to help our people?
Father!
I'm sorry, Noland.
Please don't leave yet.
Does everyone have everything?
Not everything.
You wuss.
All right, everyone, to your positions.
It's time to set sail.
We're now on our way back
to the Levineal Kingdom.
Yeah!
Noland!
I can't believe I made such a mistake.
Nolan, wait!
Set sail.
The bell why would it be ringing now?
Sorry, Nolan
Ring louder!
Nolan and the rest of them can't hear you!
Look over there!
Wait, Nolan!
Is that you, Kalgara?
Come back!
Come back, please, Noland, you've got to!
I'll ring the bell so you
can find your way back to us!
I don't want you to lose sight
of this island, because one day!
I want you to return my dear friend!
Nolan!
please come back!
I know we'll meet again?
someday Nolan!
have a safe voyage.
so
I can't come back again.
Of course I will.
I'll come back.
Someday, Kalgana!
I know we'll meet again!
I can always hear your voice.
While you wander far from home!
Gazing out at the sky.
You are just like the moon.
You never change as you
climb into the night?
But your reflection wanes.
Then you disappear, fading so silently.
Stay as you are.
Don't lose your way!
Let these words guide you.
Don't ever look back!
Don't give up on your dreams.
They're endless nights.
They come to you again and again?
Until you see the journey through.
You may not return, I
hope that you'll learn!
To put your past behind,
and just keep moving on.